William H. Twenhofel Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
William H. Twenhofel Archives
1875-1957
IPAR.001148
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
5
The archives of William H. Twenhofel including maps of Quebec, some field notebooks, and some correspondence.
Twenhofel, William Henry
Biographical Sketch
William H. Twenhofel (1875-1957), Ph.D. Yale (1912), is regarded as the patriarch of sedimentary geology. Twenhofel, who was a member of the National Research Council, retired in 1945 from an illustrious academic career at the University of Wisconsin, Madison. Twenhofel cofounded the Journal of Sedimentary Petrology, now the Journal of Sedimentary Research.
Description of the Material
Topographic maps of Anticosti Island, Quebec, and surrounding areas, along with typed copies of his field notes. Also, faunal lists and locality information from other expeditions including ones to Kansas and Texas.
Connecticut; Kansas; USA; Canada; Maps; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Maps, Series I
  - Canada. Maps of Canada., 001152
    - Map. Port-Menier 22 H, Quebec, 1976 (1: 250,000). Energy, Mines and Resources, Canada., 002222
    - Map. Ile D'Anticosti 12 E, Quebec, 1976 (1: 250,000). Energy, Mines and Resources, Canada., 002223
    - Map. Lac Manitou 22 I, Quebec, 1977 (1: 250,000). Energy, Mines and Resources, Canada., 002225
    - Map. Havre-Saint-Pierre 12 L, Quebec, 1977 (1: 250,000). Energy, Mines and Resources, Canada., 002226
    - map. Baie Du Renard 12 F, Quebec, 1976 (1: 250,000). Energy, Mines and Resources, Canada., 002224
  - Miscellaneous. Copy of Geological survey memoirs., 001153
    - Topographic map. Anticosti Island Canada Geol. Survey Memoir. [Volume=n.154]. photo copy of fig.1., 002221
- Specimen Information, Series II
  - Canada., 001155
    - Papers, notes, correspondence. Notes for figured specimens (1 - 132) for Twenhofel (1928); Anticosti Island. ca 1928, 000683
    - Missing Specimens from Twenhofel, W.H. 1928: Anticosti Island, Quebec., 000002
  - USA., 001154
    - Faunal list of Pensylvanian Brachiopods, bivalves and gastropods from Kansas [Volume=YPM.03143], 1908; 000386
- Miscellaneous, Series III
  Scope and Contents
  Miscellaneous archives including feild notes and locality information.
  - Field Notes. Notebook and notes from the field., 001157
    - Field notes. Typed field diary & notes: Anticosti Island, Quebec., 1938; 000146
    - Notebook. Field notebook for section at Arisaig: Nova Scotia. 06/1908, 07/1908, 000296
  - Locality Information. Texas locality information., 001156
    - Locality information. Locality information, Texas, Early Cretaceous., 1907; 000646